[ Cheers ]
[ 欢呼 ]
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon, ladies and
&gt;&gt;  女士们  先生们  下午好
I hope you're having a good
我希望你们到目前
Apple Developer Conference so
在苹果开发者大会上都很开心
My name is Stuart Cheshire and
我叫 Stuart Cheshire
we're going to be talking about
我会为你们介绍网络结构
We have a lot of material to
内容很多
cover so let's get right to it.
所以我们直接开始吧
This is going to be a two-part
演讲两个部分
In part 1, I'm going to give you
第一部分  我会向你们
some status updates about
介绍一些这几年
technologies that have been in
工作中的技术的
the works for many years.
更新
Explicit congestion notification
基于显示反馈的协议（ECN）
is a new way to manage flows
是通过互联网
through the internet without the
管理流量的一个新方法
cost of packet loss, and IPv6,
并且不会造成数据包丢失  而 IPv6
as I'm sure you're all aware, is
我相信你们也都知道
the emerging protocol for the
是一个新兴的互联网协议
We're going to tell you about
我们将向你们介绍一些
some changes in the networking
iOS 上的网络堆栈中的
stack on iOS and some new
一些新变化  以及一些
facilities that are now
现在可用于网络扩展的
available in network extension.
新工具
And then finally, we're going to
最后  我们将告诉你们
give you some very exciting news
一些关于多路径协议的
about multipath protocols.
好消息
The iPhones that we all have are
我们使用的 iPhone
inherently multi-path devices.
本质上都是多路径设备
They have multiple radios in
它们有不止一个电台
them, and for the most part
然而今天大多数时候
today we only use one radio at a
我们每次只使用其中一个
It's time we started having
是时候让我们开始
multipath protocols for our
使用我们的多路径设备的
multipath devices.
多路径协议了
After the break, in part 2 we're
休息过后  在第二部分
going to talk about some new
我们会谈到 URLSession 的
advances in the URL session,
一些新进展和
family of APIs.
可用的 API
We're going to give some tips
我们将会给出一些
and guidance for best practices
建议和指导
and we're going to give you some
并且会告诉你们一些
news updates on upcoming
即将发生的新进展
developments on the horizon.
的最新消息
So let's start with ECN,
那么让我们先从 ECN
Explicit Congestion
基于显示反馈的协议 开始
You sometimes hear people talk
有时你或许会听到
about a network being congested
人们谈起网络拥塞
as if that's a bad thing, but
好像是一个坏事
the job for transport protocol
然而传输协议的工作
is to send as much data as it
正是要通过网络
can through the network, and the
最大限度的传送数据
way it does that is by sending
而它的方法就是传送的
faster and faster and faster
越来越快
until it's sending too fast.
直到它传送的过快为止
In a sense, it's testing the
从某种意义上来说  它是在
network to destruction.
进行一个破坏性实验
So if the networks are
所以  如果网络的编程
programmed correctly it should
正确  它应当发生
be congested.
拥塞
On any path between two devices
在两个设备之间的任何路径上
there will be one link that has
会有一个链接  它有
the lowest throughput, the
最低的通量
lowest capacity, and that's the
最差的容量
bottleneck link.
它就是那个瓶颈
And the job of the transport
传输协议的工作
protocol is to work out its
就是去解决
share of the bottleneck link.
它在瓶颈链接中的部分
If you're sending twelve
如果你把 12 MB
megabits into a ten megabit
输入一个 10 MB 的链接
link, inevitably something has
那就不可避免的
got to go wrong.
会出错
For a short time, the package
短时间内  它可以
can be buffered in memory but
存在缓存中
when the device runs out of
但当设备缓存不足时
memory, it has no choice but to
它就没有了其他选择  只好
lose packets.
丢失数据包
And when it loses packets, that
当它丢失数据包时
is a clue to the sender that it
这是在提示发送者
was going too fast and it should
它已经运行过快
slow down a bit.
需要放慢一点
The problem is that losing
问题在于
packets is a very expensive way
通过丢失数据包来
of communicating that
向发送者来传递这个信息
information to the sender.
是代价很大的
It took battery power to send
如果数据包来自一个无线设备
those packets if they're coming
那么就需要很多电量
from a wireless device.
来发送它们
It used wireless spectrum, a
它使用无限频谱
network capacity, to send those
一种网络容量  来实现发送那些数据包
And when you drop them, they
而当你丢掉它们后
have to be retransmitted.
它们必须被重新传输
Now, those packet losses and
现在  对你的 app 而言
retransmissions are invisible to
这些数据包丢失和重新传输
your application because TCP or
都是隐形的  因为 TCP 或
the transport protocol just
传输协议就把它们解决了
Or I should say almost
或者我应该说  几乎隐形
The loss is invisible but the
数据包丢失是看不到的  但是
delay it causes is not.
它所导致的延迟却是可见的
Your application will end up
你的 app 可能需要
waiting for that retransmitted
等待那些被重新传输的
data to arrive, and that causes
数据  这就会导致
a slower, more sluggish, user
更慢  更拖沓的用户体验
With explicit congestion
有了 ECN
notification, when the
当这个
bottleneck gateway notices that
瓶颈发现
a queue is starting to form, it
数据开始排起长队等候传输的时候
doesn't wait until it runs out
它不会等到缓存不足
of memory, it sets a bit in the
它会立刻
IP packet header saying
在 IP 数据包标题中设一个字节
congestion experienced, and that
表明遭遇拥塞
serves as a hint to the sender
这就是一个对发送者的暗示
to slow down a bit, and that
发送者会放缓传输
lets the network adjust the
让网络调整
senders rate without the cost of
发送者的传输速率而不必
losing data.
损失数据
One of the side of effects of
ECN 的一个副作用是
ECN is it also encourages
它同时鼓励了 ECN
deployment of smarter queuing
在网络中配置更智能的
algorithms in the network, which
排队算法  这也是
is also a good thing.
一件好事情
If you have a very simple-minded
如果你的设备比较单纯
device with a single shared
只用一个
first-in, first-out queue that
先到先得的排队算法
fills up the queue until it runs
一直填满队列  直到
out of memory.
缓存不足
When the next packet arrives it
此时如果有一个数据包到达
has little choice.
它就没什么选择了
It has to lose data.
它只能丢失数据
So you can't really use ECN with
所以你不能在一个愚蠢的 5-0 排队算法上
a dumb 5-0 queue.
使用 ECN
You have to have smart queueing,
你得用一个智能的排队算法
and those intelligent queue
而那些智能的排队算法
algorithms that keep the queues
可以让队列保持在较短状态
short and signal congestion
并且在情况变得太糟糕之前
before it becomes very bad,
就发信号通知拥塞
that's what helps keep delays in
它们可以帮助你将
the network minimized and
网络中的延迟最小化
eliminate buffer bloat.
并且消灭缓存过满的问题
There are three participants
客户端  服务器和网络三个部分必须
that have to cooperate to make
协同工作
ECN work, the clients, the
ECN 才能工作
I'm very happy to tell you that
我很高兴告诉你们
in our latest survey of the
在我们最近一次对
Alexa top million websites,
Alexa 前 100 万网站的调查中
almost three-quarters of them
几乎四分之三
already support ECN.
都已经支持 ECN 了
Now for the most part, this was
对于大部分情况来说
not because the website
这并不是因为网络管理员
administrator made a conscious
做了一个智慧的决定
decision to support ECN, it's
来支持 ECN
simply because it's part of the
这只不过是因为它是
default Linux kernel, so they
默认的 Linux 内核的一部分
get it for free.
所以他们可以免费获取
But the good news is almost
好消息是
three-quarters of the Alexa top
Alexa前 100 万网站中的
million websites already support
几乎四分之三都已经
ECN, so that's the servers taken
支持 ECN 所以这是服务器要解决的问题了
On the client side, we have been
在客户端这方面  我们一直在
experimenting at Apple.
苹果进行实验
In iOS 10.3, for all eligible
在iOS 10.3中  对于
TCP connections on Wi-Fi,
Wi-Fi  以太网和一些移动运营商中
Ethernet and selected mobile
所有符合条件的 TCP 连接
carriers, we toss a coin and
我们抛硬币随机选取
half of the TCP connections will
一半的 TCP 连接将
request ECN.
提出 ECN 请求
We did this to gauge whether the
我们这么做是为了估测
internet was safe for ECN.
网络是否对 ECN 安全
Five years ago, this experiment
五年前  这样对实验
would probably have produced
或许会产生
different results.
不同的结果
There were old firewalls and
有的旧的防火墙
middle boxes that might have got
和 middlebox 会因为
confused by the ECN bits.
ECN 而混乱
The good news is we did this
好消息是我们
experiment on a massive scale
在全世界范围内大面积进行这个实验
worldwide and we didn't hear any
并未看到
news, we didn't hear any
任何新闻  并没有听到任何
customer complaints that the
客户抱怨
internet was broken.
网络瘫痪
In the AWD metrics that gathered
在我们为
ourselves to monitor how the
考察设备表现如何而检测的
devices were performing, we saw
各项 AWD 指标中
no discernable difference in
我们没有发现任何在
packet loss, retransmission,
数据包丢失  重新传输
reordering, any of the other
重新排序或其他我们所关心的
metrics that we care about.
指标方面有任何明显区别
So it would appear that the
所以  看起来
internet is now safe for ECN.
现在的网络使用 ECN 是安全的
Now we were not expecting to see
现在我们已经不再期待会看到
any actual congestion marking
任何网络拥塞标记
happening because until the
因为在
clients and servers are doing
客户端和服务器执行
ECN, there's an awful lot of
ECN 之前  有太多太多事情
incentive for the network
刺激网络运营商
operators to start deploying it.
来使用它了
And indeed, we saw very little
确实  在世界上大部分地方
congestion marking in most of
我们几乎都看不到拥塞标记了
But then we looked a bit further
然而当我们再进一步观察
and we saw in Mexico of all the
我们看到在墨西哥
device reports we collected 3%
我们采集的的设备报告中
of them had seen at least one
3% 的数据中
congestion experience mark on a
至少有一个包经历了拥塞
In France it was 6%.
在法国  这个数字是 6%
In Argentina it was 30%.
在阿根廷  这个数字是 30%
I'm not sure what they're doing
我不知道阿根廷人在搞什么
in Argentina, but it would
但是看起来
appear that they've already
他们已经在
started deploying ECN, and if
开始部署 ECN 了
that's true keep up the good
如果这是真的
work Argentina.
干得好  阿根廷
That's fantastic.
这就很神奇了
So to summarize, servers are
总结一下
supporting ECN, clients are
服务器支持 ECN 客户端也
supporting ECN, and in iOS 11
支持 ECN 我们已经判定在 iOS 11
now that we've determined it's
它是安全的
safe, 100% of eligible
100%的可用连接
connections will be using ECN,
都会在无线网络  以太网或
on Wi-Fi, Ethernet, and selected
一些特定的运营商中使用
If you work for a carrier and
如果你在运营商工作
you're not in this program,
而不在这个项目中
contact your carrier relations
你可以联系你的运营商
person at Apple and they can get
在苹果的公关人员  他们会帮你
you signed into this program to
进入这个项目
support ECN on your networks
让你的网络也支持 ECN
So now the stage is set.
现在舞台已经搭好
The clients are doing it.
用户在使用它
The servers are doing it.
服务器也在使用它
Any ISP or network operator in
世界上的任何 ISP 或网络运营商
the world can deploy ECN and see
可以使用
immediate user experience
并且马上使他们的用户
benefits for their users.
获得更好的体验
One common misunderstanding
一个关于 ECN 的常见的误区
about ECN is that it has to be
就是它必须在整个网络的
supported end to end on the
所有路径上都实现
entire path across the internet,
端到端的支持
and that's not true.
但事实并不是这样
There is only one place that
你只需要让
needs to support ECN for you to
一处支持 ECN 就可以享受它
get the benefit.
带来的福利
As I said, on any path between
如我所说  在两个设备之间的
two devices there is generally
任何路径上  一般都有一个
one link which is the bottleneck
链接是瓶颈链接
link, and for most of you at
对于你们中的大部分
home with your residential
在家使用宽带的人而言
internet connections that
那个瓶颈其实
bottleneck link is an artificial
是人为设置的
You may have paid for 10
你可能购买的是 10MB
megabits or 20 megabits or 50
或者 20MB 又或者 50MB 的
megabits of service and the way
服务  而你的 ISP 供应商
your ISP provides that service
提供这个服务的方式
is they artificially throttle
就是人为地把数据
your data to the rate you've
掐到你付钱购买的那个速度上
So the one queue on your path
所以你几乎所有连接的
for almost all connections is
路径上的一个队列
the one that exists at your
就是存在于你的
ISP's headend equipment where
ISP 的前端设备的那个
they are artificially throttling
你的数据在这个前端设备上被节流
That is the only place on the
这是路径上唯一
path that needs to mark
需要通过设置二进位
congestion by setting the bit
来标记拥塞的地方
instead of by discarding the
而非通过丢失数据包
packet, and your customers get
而你的用户可以获得
the benefit of a faster more
一个更快  响应更良好的
responsive internet.
网络环境
So with that, I would like to
我想请出
invite my colleague, David
我的同事 David
Schinazzi, to come up on stage
Schinazzi 到台上来
and give you some more news
给你们讲一些新的信息
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon, everyone.
&gt;&gt;  大家下午好
My name is David Schinazzi, I'm
我叫 David Schinazzi 是一个
a core networking engineer here
苹果的核心网络工程师
at Apple, and I'm going to start
我想首先
off by talking about IPv6,
谈一谈 IPv6
giving you a status update.
给你们一些最新的情况
And especially if you're writing
尤其是你正在
apps that use the internet
写一些要用到网络的 app 的话
today, well you actually really
你需要关注一下
So as some of you might know,
你们之中也许有人知道
yesterday was the 5th
昨天是全球 IPv6
anniversary of World IPv6
投入使用五周年
So five years ago yesterday many
五年前的昨天
content provider across the
网上的许多内容提供者
internet got together and
聚到一起
enabled IPv6.
启用了 IPv6
And it worked well so they kept
它运行良好  所以他们
it on, but what's happened
没有关闭它  但是那之后发生了什么呢？
This is a graph of the client
这个图像显示的是
device adoption over the years.
在过去几年中的客户端设备使用情况
At the time less than 1% of
那时候  不到 1% 的设备
devices supported IPv6.
支持 IPv6
Now we're almost at 20%.
现在  数字几乎达到 20%
And a really important point is
很重要的一点是
that if you're writing apps for
如果你为苹果设备写 app 的话
Apple devices, on the markets
在苹果设备使用最多的市场
where we see most Apple devices
这些数字一般来说
these numbers are generally
会更高
Especially in the case of
尤其是对蜂窝数据来说
cellular, almost all carriers
几乎与我们合作的
that we work with now deploy
所有运营商现在都使用
dual stack, meaning that they
双栈  就是说他们
offer both IPv4 and IPv6.
同时提供 IPv4 和 IPv6
And the great news is, it works
好消息是  这样的效果更好
So we've actually measured this
所以我们事实上
based on a lot of the
依据很多我们的设备所作出的连接
connections our devices make.
而进行估测
The HTP request load in 15 to
HTTPS 请求的加载速度提高了
30% faster, which means that if
15-30% 这意味着
you actually have two apps side
如果你同时打开了两个 app
by side, you will notice the
你就会发现其中的区别
Your customers will see a
你的用户也会看到区别
So if you don't know if your
所以如果你至今仍不知道
server supports IPv6 today,
是否支持 IPv6
definitely check, contact your
你需要检查一下
server team and make sure they
联系你的服务器团队  确保他们
support IPv6.
能够支持 IPv6
You can't afford to let this
你可无法负担得起
performance wane on the table.
一直拖着不用它
Another important trend that I
另一个重要的我想谈的趋势
like to talk about is NAT64.
是 NAT64
So we started talking about this
我们从两年前的 WWDC
at WWDC two years ago, and then
开始讨论这件事
we made it an app store
去年我们把它变成了一个 App Store 的准入要求
requirement last year but now
现在它来了
It's in production for several
它已经在一个
months now on a major carrier in
美国的主流运营商上
the U.S., every single device is
投入使用了几个月  每个设备
v6 only.
都是只支持 v6 的
They don't have an IPv4 address,
它们没有 IPv4 地址
they can only talk using IPv6.
它们只能通过 IPv6 交流
So that doesn't mean that you
但那并不意味着你
can't talk to v4 servers.
不能与 v4 服务器交流
Thanks to a box on the network
因为有一个叫做 NAT64 的网络盒子
called the NAT64, devices can
设备就仍然可以
still connect to those servers,
连接到那些服务器
however, you're not getting the
然而  这样你就无法获得
performance benefits that we're
那些我们谈到的
talking about by using v6
本地使用 v6 的性能优势了
However, what's really important
但是  最重要的是
is that the app needs to make
app 需要确保它
sure it supports IPv6.
支持 IPv6
If it tries to connect to IPv4,
如果它试图连接到 IPv4
that will not work.
这是行不通的
So how do you do that?
那么你要怎么做呢
It's very simple.
其实非常简单
If you use our higher level API
如果你使用我们的高级 API
such as URLSession CFNetwork,
比如 URLSession CFNetwork
the system libraries do all the
系统库会替你完成所有这些
heavy lifting for you.
繁重工作
You don't need to worry about
你不需要担心任何
IPv4, IPv6, any of that.
IPv4 或 IPv6 的事情
It just works.
它会自动运行
What you really want to avoid is
你需要避免的是
using Legacy IPv4 on the APIs,
在 API 上使用 Legacy IPv4
directly typing in an IPv4
直接在你的 app 上
address into your app, or using
输入一个 IPv4 地址  或者使用
preflight checks.
预先检查
For example, if you check if the
比方说  如果你在
device is IPv4 address before
进行连接之前检查
making connection, that won't
设备是否是 IPv4 地址
work anymore.
就是行不通的
And why -- another reason why
并且
you should really care is that
你需要考虑它的另一个原因是
this is an app review
这是一个 app 的审查标准
It's required for any app,
任何 app 不管是新的
either new or an update, to get
还是一个升级版本  要在 app store 上架
on the app store.
都必须具备此性能
Every one of them is tested on
每一个 app 都会在一个
an IPv6 only NAT64 network, and
只有 IPv6 的 NAT64 网络环境中被测试
if it doesn't work you will not
如果它无法运行  你就无法
make it onto the store.
让它上架
However, I really want to
然而  我要祝贺
congratulate all you developers
所有的开发者
because you've fixed all of your
因为你们都已经修正了
apps and we now almost never
你们的 app  我们现在已经几乎
have to reject anything.
不用拒绝任何 app 了
So great job there.
干得好
If you want more tips on how to
如果你希望我给出一些关于
really make sure everything
如何保证一切正常的
works, there is a great section
建议  开发者网站上有一个
on the developer website called
部分叫做
supporting IPv6 DNS64/NAT64
支持 supporting IPv6 DNS64/NAT64
networks.
网站
Feel free to also join us in the
你也随时可以加入我们
labs tomorrow and Friday with
明天和周五的实验室  提出任何问题
Now I'd like to switch gears and
现在我想换个话题
talk about networking on the
聊聊在设备本身的网络架构问题
device itself, and introduce
然后向你们介绍
something this year that we're
今年我们称之为用户空间网络架构的
calling user space networking.
东西
You're probably familiar with
你或许对
the traditional model of a
网络堆栈的传统模型很熟悉
networking stack where a lot of
在这种模型中
the hard work is done inside the
内核承担了很多繁重的工作
So protocol such as Wi-Fi, IP,
所以诸如 Wi-Fi  IP
TCP are all handled inside the
TCP 等协议都是在内核中处理的
Then there's a boundary called
那样就有一个边界叫做
the BSD socket API, and
BSD socket API
everything else is handled
而其他的都在 app 内部
inside the app.
进行处理
And by that I mean inside the
我的意思是  在
app process, not necessarily
app 运行过程之内  而不
inside your code.
是在你的代码之内
It could be inside system
它有可能在系统库里面
libraries, but protocols like
但是 HTTPS 或者 TLS 这样的协议
HTP and TLS are handled inside
就会被在这个过程中被处理
What we're introducing for the
在 iOS 11 中我们第一次提出了
first time with iOS 11 is we're
我们正在
unifying everything inside the
将 app 中的一切都统一起来
And what this means is that the
这就意味着
protocols can interact much
各个协议的联系可以更紧密
tighter and everything is more
一切都会具有更高性能
We've actually noticed great CPU
我们注意到它会大量
usage reductions which allows
减少 CPU 的使用量
you to spend more time on
让你能有更多
animations, but also at the end
的动画时间  不仅如此
of the day users have more
最终用户会有更长的续航时间
One point to note is that you
我要提醒的是
will only be able to get this if
你只有在使用一个
you're using a high level IPI
高等级 IPI
such as URLSession.
比如 URLSession 时才可以获取这个协议
You will not get these benefits
如果你依然在使用 CBSD 插座的话
if you're still using like a
你就无法获得这些性能优势了
And another point that I would
我还要提出的一点
like to make about this is that
就是
Network Kernel Extensions, which
Network Kernel Extensions
rely on these legacy BSD sockets
它依赖于内核中的
inside the kernel, will soon be
传统 BSD 插座，我们很快就不会再使用了
So if you're using those, please
如果你还在使用它们的话
start right now transitioning to
请现在就开始向
the network extension framework
网络扩展框架过渡
and come talk to us if you have
如果你有任何问题的话
any questions about this.
可以来找我们讨论
Speaking of the network
说到网络扩展框架
extension framework, I'd like to
我想向你们介绍
introduce two new APIs this year
关于Wi-Fi配置和
regarding Wi-Fi configuration
扩展 DNS 的两款今年新开发的 API
So the new framework was
新的框架是两年前
introduced two years ago and was
提出的
built with four main temples,
有四个主要部分
NEVPNManager allows you to
NEVPNManager 允许你配置
configure the VPN stack on the
设备上的 VPN 堆栈
NETunnelProvider allow you to
NETunnelProvider 允许你
build your own customer VPN
构建自己的用户 VPN 协议
NEHotspotHelper allow you to
NEHotspotHelper 允许你
customize how your device
自定义你的设备如何
authenticates to Wi-Fi hotspots.
验证 Wi-Fi 热点
And finally, NEFilterProvider
最后 NEFilterProvider
allows you to build a secure
允许你建立一个安全的
on-device content filter.
基于设备的内容过滤器
I won't go into more details on
我不会过于详细地
these four parts of the API,
解释这个 API 的四个部分
however there's a great WWDC
不过两年前有一场 WWDC 会议
session from two years ago that
讲了很多关于这个的细节
So let's dive into any hotspot
现在我们来讨论关于热点配置的问题
You may have had this experience
你们或许有过这样的经历
before where you bought a really
买来一个
nice smart camera.
智能相机
You take it out of the box and
你把它从盒子里拿出来
it tells you, oh join this Wi-Fi
它就告诉你  在你的 iphone 上加入这个
network on your iPhone to be
Wi-Fi 网络来
able to configure the app.
配置这个 app
And so in the app it tells you,
然后在这个 app 里它会告诉你
oh go to settings, Wi-Fi, type
打开设置  选择 Wi-Fi
it in, and that's pretty
输入密码  整个过程非常麻烦
The user could mistype the
用户可能会输错密码
They could also not remember
他们也可能会忘记
where the settings app is.
设置 app 在哪
And we had a lot of requests
我们收到了很多
from developers for a better
开发者的请求  寻求一个
solution for this.
更好的解决方案
And what we've added is this
我们就添加了这个
simple API that allows you to do
简单的 API 允许你
everything from the app.
做任何可以在 app 中做的操作
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
Now the user never has to leave
现在用户再也不必
the app anymore, they just get a
关掉 app 他们会收到一个
prompt to make sure they will
提示以确认他们
actually want to do this.
是否想做某个操作
They click join, they associate
他们点击“加入”  就可以
to the Wi-Fi.
联入 Wi-Fi
Simple as that.
就这么简单
You can even set up this API to
你可以把这个 API 设置成
be temporary.
暂时的
So if you're building a
如果你正在为一个智能设备
configuration app for a smart
开发一个配置 appc
device, you only really want to
你只会希望你在用 app 的时候
be connected to that Wi-Fi if
才联入这个 Wi-Fi
So if the user decides to leave
所以  如果用户想要
your app and go do something
关掉你的 app 然后
else, the device will
做其他的事情
automatically disassociate from
设备会自动断开这个
Wi-Fi and join -- rejoin their
Wi-Fi 并且加入
other Wi-Fi networks.
其他的 Wi-Fi 网络
You can also use this API for
你也可以用这个 API 达到
the traditional sense of using
传统意义上使用 Wi-Fi 的目的
Wi-Fi.
比如  如果你正在为一个连锁咖啡店
an app for chain of cafes and
开发 app
would like your users to
希望你的用户能够
automatically join the Wi-Fi in
在这些咖啡店里自动
these cafes.
联入 Wi-Fi
And of course, the CPI supports
当然 CPI 支持
all the modes of authentication
所有我们的 Wi-Fi 协议栈今天
that our Wi-Fi stack supports
支持的所有认证方式
To show you just how easy this
让我来向你们展示这有多简单
is, here's a little code sample
这是一些关于以上两个例子
for these two examples.
的示范代码
So if you want to configure a
如果你想配置一个照相机
camera, just create a
你只需要
configuration with the name of
用 Wi-Fi 的名字和密码
the Wi-Fi and the password.
创建一个配置
Set the join one's property to
然后设置要加入的那个网络的属性
indicate that you want to
表明你想在
dissociate when the device --
设备或者用户关掉
when the user leaves your app,
你的 app 时断开连接
and just apply the
然后应用这个配置
Then check the result value for
然后检查结果是否成功
In the café use case which is
咖啡店那个例子其实
even simpler, just create a
更加简单  你只需要创建一个
configuration, apply it and
配置  应用
you're done.
然后就完成了
Now I'd like to talk about any
现在我想谈谈
DNS proxy provider.
DNS proxy provider
The CPL let's you customize how
CPL 允许你自定义
the iPhone or other iOS device
iPhone 或其他 iOS 设备
interacts with DNS, so this API
与 DNS 互动的方式
allows you to, in its simplest
所以这个 API 就是允许你用最
mode, simply redirect all the
简单的方式将所有请求都
inquiries to a resolver that you
转到你自己的一个解析器上
For example, if that resolver
比方说  如果这个
has better features, or you can
解析器有更好的功能
even use this to get the
你甚至可以用它来获取
individual DNS queries and send
单个的 DNS 请求并且
them over a custom protocol such
通过一个自定义协议发送他们
as DNS over TLS or DNS over GTP.
比如基于 TLS 的 DNS 或基于 GTP 的 DNS 等
So that was an update on network
那么这就是今年关于
extension this year.
网络扩展的一些最新进展
As a quick reminder, this is a
一个小提示  这是一个
very powerful API so it requires
非常强大的 API 所以
X-code capabilities and
它做任何事情都必须要求
entitlements, and also user
X-code 能力和权限
consent for everything it does.
也包括用户的同意
Now I would like to invite
现在我想请
Christoph Paasch on the stage to
Christoph Paasch 到台上
talk about multipath devices.
谈谈多路径设备的有关内容
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, David.
&gt;&gt;  谢谢 David
Hello, everybody.
大家好
My name is Christoph Paasch.
我是 Christoph Paasch
I'm a networking engineer at
我是苹果的一个网络工程师
Apple, and I will show you the
我将会向你们展示
new technologies we have in iOS
我们在 iOS 11 中提供的
11 that will improve the
能够提高你的
networking of your applications
app 在移动设备上的网络连接的
on mobile devices.
一些新技术
So, you have all experienced it.
你们肯定都经历过
You are using your application
你正在使用 app
and your application is
而你的 app 正在
downloading something from the
从互联网上下载东西
internet, and while you're using
你一边用着 app
it, you are walking out of your
一边从家走出来
Now as you're walking out of
现在  当你正从你家
your home, you're also walking
走出来时  你也正
farther away from your Wi-Fi
离你的 Wi-Fi 接入点
access point, which basically
越来越远  这基本上
means the connection that you
意味着你在 Wi-Fi 上创建的连接
have created on Wi-Fi is getting
也正在变得
slower and slower, and
越来越慢
ultimately your application is
最终你的 app 也会
because it cannot download the
因为它已经无法从网上
content from the internet.
下载内容了
And it will only be able to
只有当你与蜂窝数据
continue again when you have
重新建立了一个连接之后
then created a new connection
它才能够
over to cellular link.
重新再开始下载
Now, the reason why this happens
现在  这件事发生的
is because the protocols that I
原因是我今天使用的
use today have been specified
协议是几十年之前
several decades ago and they
开发的  它被创建出来时
have not been designed with
还没有考虑到
mobile devices in mind.
移动设备的问题
Now at Apple, we are aware of
现在  苹果在几年前
this problem since several years
就已经意识到了这个问题
now, and we have technologies in
我们在 iOS 中有相应的技术
iOS that try to address exactly
来对症下药
We have Wi-Fi assist since iOS
从 iOS 9 起我们推出了 Wi-F Assist
9, and now in iOS 11 we are
现在在 iOS 11 中
pushing this even farther.
我们进一步更新了这一功能
We are introducing a new
我们推出了一个
multipath transport protocol
新的多路径传输协议
that is called Multipath TCP,
叫做 Multipath TCP
and we will open it as a public
并且在 iOS 11 中我们将把它开源
API in iOS 11.
作为一个公共的 API
Now, let's take a step back
现在我们先
first and let's take a look at
回顾一下
what are the scenarios that we
我们想要解决的是
are trying to address here.
哪些情况
So when your phone is connected
当你的手机联入
to a good Wi-Fi network, what
一个良好的 Wi-Fi 网络时
will happen is you create a
你会创建一个连接
connection and you will only
并且你只会从
download from the Wi-Fi network.
Wi-Fi 网络中进行下载
Now as your user is walking out
如果你的用户正在
of the Wi-Fi, walking away from
走出 Wi-Fi 的覆盖范围  或者离开
it, what happens is the signal
Wi-Fi 的接入点  信号强度就会
strength will get lower and
越来越低
lower, and the connection will
连接也会越来越慢
get slower and ultimately it
而最终它会
completely stops.
完全停止
What happens then is you will
接下来如果你还想
need to -- if you want to keep
继续下载数据的话
on downloading your data, you
你就需要
will need to create a new
在数据网络上创建
connection on the cellular link
一个新的连接
and from that moment on you are
然后从那一刻起
good to go again and your
你就再次一切就绪了
application responds again to
你的 app 又可以响应
the data that is coming from the
从服务器发出的数据了
If you want to handle this kind
如果你想应对这个情况
of scenario, inside your
在你的 app 的
application at the application
应用层面
layer, there are quite a few
你需要做以下
things that you need to do.
几件事情
First, you will need to record
首先你需要记录
everything that you are doing
你在做的一切事情
because you never know when
因为你不知道什么时候
Wi-Fi is going to drop out so
Wi-Fi 会断开
you will need to remember what
所以你就需要记住
you have been doing and what
你所做过的一切操作以及
were the request that are in
正在传输的请求
Second, you will need a way to
第二  你需要一种可以
detect that Wi-Fi is getting
检测到 Wi-Fi 的方法
worse, so you need to somehow
所以你需要设法
monitor the progress of the
监测 Wi-Fi 连接的进展情况
Now, once you have finally
现在  一旦你
detected that Wi-Fi, it's no
发现 Wi-Fi 已经不可用
longer available and can no
或者已经无法
longer deliver the service that
提供你需要的服务时
you need, you will need to
你就需要
create a new connection over
创建一个数据网络中的新连接
That means you need to do a DSN
这就是说你需要进行一个
handshake, a TCP handshake, and
DSN 重连 TCP 重连和
a TLS handshake.
一个 TLS 重连
And only after all those steps
只有在这几个步骤完成之后
you can finally send your
你才可以通过
request over the cellular
蜂窝数据接口
interface and your application
来实现数据传输
can make progress again.
你的 app 才可以继续运行
Doing this at the application
在应用层面完成这些
layer is very cumbersome and
操作是非常繁琐的
that's one of those scenarios
而这只是我们想要解决的
that we want to address.
情况之一
Let's take a look at another
我们来看另一个情况
It's basically when you're in a
大概是当你在一个
very poor Wi-Fi scenario.
很差的 Wi-Fi 下的情况
For example, you're sitting in a
比方说  你坐在一个
café and you're connecting to
咖啡馆里  你连接的是
the public hotspot.
一个公共热点
Now, usually this hotspot
通常这个公共热点
probably works very well,
都是运行良好的
however, sometimes there is some
然而有时候很多
other users also in this café
其他用户也在咖啡馆里
and maybe one of them is
也许他们中的一个正在
downloading a huge file.
下载一个特别大的文件
And because very often there's a
由于大部分时候
lack of smart queue management
这个网络并没有一个
in the network, this download of
智能的队列管理系统
this huge file will create a
下载这个大型文件可能会
large chunk of buffer bloat
在网络内部造成
inside the network, and this
缓存过满  而这个
buffer bloat is making all other
塞子将会使其他
internet connections also very
网络连接都特别慢
And so it means basically your
这就意味着
application will no more be able
你的 app 将无法
to download the traffic from the
从互联网
data, from the internet.
下载数据了
If you want to address such kind
如果你想在
of scenarios inside your
你的 app 中解决
application, you would want to
这种问题
basically create a connection on
你需要在 Wi-Fi 和数据网络上都
Wi-Fi and on cell, and as soon
创建一个接口  当你
as you realize that Wi-Fi is no
发现 Wi-Fi 情况已经
more good enough because the
不够好
delay is just getting too high,
数据延迟已经过高时
you want to send a little bit of
你可以把一小部分数据
data over to cellular network so
通过蜂窝数据传输
that you can make progress
这样你的 app 就可以继续运行
And as soon as Wi-Fi is getting
一旦 Wi-Fi 再次变好
better again, you want to switch
你可以再次
all your traffic back to Wi-Fi.
把你所有的流量都切换到 Wi-Fi 连接
Doing this at the application
在应用层面完成
layer would be extremely
这个操作可以说极其困难
So, this brings me to Wi-Fi
这让我们开发了 Wi-Fi
Assist, which is a technology
Assist  它是我们从
that we since iOS 9 and that
iOS 9 起为了
tries to address these kind of
解决这些情况而推出的技术
Wi-Fi Assist is triggered
只要我们在一个不太理想的 Wi-Fi 环境下
whenever we are in a marginal
Wi-Fi Assist 就会被打开
Wi-Fi scenario, which means the
不太理想的意思就是
signal strength of Wi-Fi is very
Wi-Fi 的信号强度非常低
And whenever the phone and iOS
只要手机和 iOS
is detecting this, what happens
发现了这一点
is we will play a fittest wins
我们会在
out contest which between Wi-Fi
Wi-Fi 和数据网络之间
and cell.
优胜劣汰
So when you are creating a new
当你创建一个新的
connection, we will first
连接时  我们会首先
attempt to create disconnection
试图关闭与
on Wi-Fi.
Wi-Fi 的连接
And shortly after that where if
之后很快
this connection hasn't been
如果这个连接没有被成功创建
established, we will go on and
我们会继续
create a connection over cell so
创建一个对数据网络的链接
that way we are able-- if
这样我们就可以  如果
cellular data wins, we will
蜂窝数据胜出的话
start using the cellular link.
就开始使用数据网络
So this will include a little
那么这会使用
bit of cellular data usage and
一点点蜂窝数据
so as part of Wi-Fi Assist we
所以作为 Wi-Fi Assist 的一部分  我们
are limiting the amount of data
限制你的 app
that your application could use
在这种情况
as part of this scenario.
可以使用的数据总量
We have had great success with
我们在 Wi-Fi Assist 的使用上
using Wi-Fi Assist, because it
获得了很大成功  因为它可以
is able to establish a
在 Wi-Fi 情况不好时
connection even if Wi-Fi is not
建立起一个连接
And we have seen a great
我们也看到了
reduction in the terms of the
数据卡壳情况
number of data stalls.
大量缩减
If your application is using the
如果你的 app 使用
URLSession API, you will get
URLSession API 你就可以免费
Wi-Fi Assist for free.
获得 Wi-Fi Assist
It is just going to work.
它会自动生效
You don't need to do any changes
你不需要在你的 API 中
in your API.
做任何更改
inside the servers, it just
做任何更改  它会自动工作
Now the thing with Wi-Fi Assist
现在 Wi-Fi Assist
is that it does this at flow
的问题是它是在一个数据流创建时
creation time.
进行这些工作的
And as I explained earlier, once
正如我之前所说的  一旦
a flow is established it will
一个数据流被创建了
stick to this interface.
它就会一直呆在这个接口上
So if Wi-Fi Assist was used and
所以如果使用了
for some reason the Wi-Fi
而因为某些原因
interface won the race, this
Wi-Fi 接口胜出
flow that has been established
这个已经创建的数据流
on a Wi-Fi interface is going to
将会一直呆在这个 Wi-Fi 接口上
So even if Wi-Fi afterwards is
即使在那之后 Wi-Fi
getting worse, this flow is
开始变糟  这个数据流
going to get slower and slower
会变得越来越慢
and it will eventually stall.
最终卡住
So, the only way to address this
所以  为了解决这个问题
problem is by creating new
唯一的方法是创建一个
protocol that is understood by
新的客户端和服务器
the client and the server.
都遵守的协议
And this brings me to Multipath
这就是 Multipath TCP
Multipath TCP is the protocol
Multipath TCP 是一种
that has been designed
专门为移动设备设计的
specifically for mobile devices.
协议
Multipath TCP is specified by
Multipath TCP 由 IETF 提出
the IETF as a standard, and it
作为一个标准
provides the exact same service
它提供和 TCP 完全一样的服务
as TCP, which means it is a
这意味着它是一个
reliable byte stream service.
可靠的字节流服务
So if you are using HTP, if you
如果你正在使用 HTTP
are using TLS, HTTPS, Multipath
使用 TLS 或 HTTPS 你可以使用 Multipath
TCP can be used just for that.
TCP
Additionally, it is built on top
另外 它建立在 TCP 之上
of TCP, so it benefits from the
所以它吸收了我们
years and years of experience
年复一年开发 TCP
that we have with developing
的大量经验
And it benefits from the
它也得益于
reliability and from the
它从 TCP 提供的
congestion control that TCP is
拥塞控制中得到的
providing.
可靠性
What it does on top of TCP is
在 TCP 之上
that it provides a way to
它提供的是一种
seamlessly move traffic from the
将流量从
Wi-Fi interface over to the
Wi-Fi 接口无缝对接到
cellular interface whenever it
蜂窝数据接口的方式
realizes that Wi-Fi is not good
无论什么时候它发现 Wi-Fi 环境
enough, and it also allows to
不够好  它同时允许
move the traffic back again so
把流量接回 Wi-Fi 接口
that your application is not
这样你的 app 就不会
consuming cellular data.
消耗过多的移动数据
It is also able to choose the
如果你有一个对延迟敏感的
best interface if you have a
交互式数据流  它还可以
latency-sensitive and
帮你选择最佳接口
So, let's dive a little bit
那么让我们再
deeper into Multipath TCP.
进一步深入了解一下 Multipath TCP
If you are building your
如果你在 URLSession API 上
application on top of the
开发 app
URLSession API, Multipath TCP
那么 Multipath TCP
sits just below this.
就正好在它下面
So as you'll layer, you don't
所以对你来说  你并不需要
really need to worry about those
担心那些
different interfaces.
不同的接口
Now what happens is, when you
现在  当你
are sending data, you're sending
发送数据时  你是在
something through the URLSession
通过 URLSession
API, this data will go through
API 来发送的  这部分数据
your URLSession over the MPTCP
将会通过在 MPTCP 堆栈上的 URLSession
stack, and the MPTCP stack is in
实现发送  而 MPTCP 堆栈
charge of scheduling this
负责将这些数据规划
traffic over either Wi-Fi or the
使它通过 Wi-Fi 或蜂窝数据发送
Now how does it do this
那么它是如何实现
scheduling over Wi-Fi and Cell,
在 Wi-Fi 和蜂窝数据之间的规划的呢
well it does this by creating
它是通过创建
the so-called TCP Subflows.
所谓的 TCP 子数据流实现的
Those TCP subflows, one for each
这些 TCP 子流
interface are actually
每个接口都有一个  它们实际上是
full-fledged TCP connections,
完整的 TCP 连接
and MPTCP is in charge of making
而 MPTCP 就要负责
sure that the data gets sent
确保数据是通过它们
over either of them.
实现传输的
It is also in charge of creating
它还负责创造
and destroying those TCP
和销毁这些 TCP 子流
So again, at your layer on top
那么  从你在
of your URLSession, you are not
URLSession 之上的这一层面来说
even aware of those subflows.
你可能根本都意识不到这些子流的存在
MPTCP decides when to create
MPTCP 决定什么时候创建
those subflows and when to
这些子流  什么时候
destroy them again.
把它们销毁
Now, Multipath TCP is actually
现在  其实 Multipath TCP 已经并不是
not that new.
那么新鲜的一件事了
We have been using it since
我们在 iOS 中其实
several years now at Apple in
已经使用了好几年了
iOS, and we are using since iOS
我们从 iOS 7 开始就把它用到了 Siri 上
Now, Siri is a very particular
现在 Siri 是一个很特别的 app
Many people, when they are using
对很多人而言  当他们使用 Siri 时
it, they are actually walking
他们可能正在
out of their home because, for
走出家门  举个例子
example, while walking out of
当他们正往外走时
their home they are asking Siri
他们叫 Siri
to send a message to a friend,
帮他们给一个朋友发信息
for example.
打个比方
And so Siri is very often in
所以 Siri 经常遇到
this scenerio where Wi-Fi is
这种 Wi-Fi 变得
getting worse and worse and
越来越糟糕
ultimately the connection drops.
最终连接断掉的情况
Now the thing is, this
现在问题在于  这种
connection that Siri created to
Siri 为了发送
send the data to the server and
数据到服务器然后获取
get a response back, this data,
响应而建立的连接
this connection, is very
这种数据  是非常
critical because if this
关键的  因为如果这个
connection breaks, the response
连接崩溃的话
is not going to come back.
它将无法获得响应
And so it's also very time
它同时对时间也
sensitive because the user is
极其敏感  因为用户往往
often literally looking at the
真的是盯着
phone and waiting for the
手机屏幕等待它的回复
And it's also a very low volume
同时它也是一个容量很低的连接
There's not much data being
并没有发送很多数据
So even if we incur -- send a
所以  即使我们有时候
little bit of data over the
用蜂窝数据来发送一些数据
cellular link, it is not going
也不会占用很多流量
to be a lot of data, only a few
因为不会是很多数据  最多几个 KB
Now, because of all those free
现在  因为这些免费的
characteristics, the way we are
性能  我们对 Siri
using a Multipath TCP for Siri
使用 Multipath TCP
is in such a way that whenever a
的方式成了
user uses Siri, we create a
每当一个用户使用 Siri 时
subflow over Wi-Fi and a TCP
我们在 Wi-Fi 接口和蜂窝数据接口上
subflow over the cellular link.
各创建一个 TCP 数据子流
And we make those subflows ready
我们让这些子流随时都
to send the data right away so
做好马上发送数据的准备
that we get a very low latency
确保我们不会遭遇太多的响应延迟
When we are scheduling traffic
当我们安排数据流时
we will prefer the Wi-Fi link,
我们会首选 Wi-Fi 连接
but if we realize that the
但是如果我们发现
latency on the Wi-Fi link is too
Wi-Fi 连接上的延迟太高
high to get a quick response
无法快速获得响应时
back, then we do not hesitate to
我们就会毫不犹豫地
send traffic over the cellular
在蜂窝数据连接上发送数据
Now, during all of this for
现在  关于
Multipath TCP we have seen great
Multipath TCP 的这些应用我们都取得了很大成功
In one particular metric which
有一个特别的标准
we call the time to first word,
我们称之为第一个词时间
which means the time it takes
意思是用户在屏幕上
until the user sees the first
看到第一个词之前
spoken word appear on the
所需要到时间
screen, this metric has been
这个标准
reduced into worse-case scenario
在最糟糕的情况下
which means when Wi-Fi was very
就是 Wi-Fi 已经极其差的情况
bad, which we call like the 95th
我们把它称之为 第 95 个百分值
percentile, this metric has been
它已经
improved by 20%.
提高了 20%
So in terms of latency
就减少延迟而言
reduction, we were able to bring
由于 Multipath TCP 的存在
down the latency thanks, to
我们也得以大幅缩短延迟时间
And also as users are typically
由于用户往往
walking out of the Wi-Fi zone
在走出 Wi-Fi 区域时
when using Siri, we have reduced
使用 Siri 我们把
the amount of network failures,
网络失误
and we have reduced it by 5
已经比
times compared to when normal
普通 TCP 情况下降低了五倍
So, we have seen great success
我们在 Siri 身上已经
with Siri and we also received a
取得了成功  我们也收到了
lot requests from new developers
很多新开发者的请求
that we should open up the API
希望我们可用公开
for Multipath TCP.
Multipath TCP 的 API
Now, in iOS 11 we are making
现在  在 iOS 11 中  我们走出了
this step and we are opening up
这一步  我们向你们公开了
the API for you to start using
这个 API 方便你们开始使用
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
So in order to start using the
要开始使用这个 API 之前
API, there are three things that
我需要告诉你们三件事
I will have to talk to you about
我会在接下来的
it, and I would come to each of
一分钟后挨个谈到
First of all, because it's a new
首先  因为它是一个新的
protocol we will need service
协议  我们将会需要服务器支持
Once you have the service
一旦你拥有了服务器支持
support you can start to choose
你可以开始选择
which of your connections would
你的哪些连接
benefit from MPTCP.
可以从 MPTCP 中获益
And then once we've chosen the
然后  当我们选好了
connections, you can then as a
这些连接以后  第三步
third step start opting into the
你可以开始选择加入
URLSession API.
URLSession API
So let's start with the server
我们从 Multipath TCP 的
support for Multipath TCP.
服务器支持开始吧
Now, it is a very new protocol
目前  它是一个比较新的协议
and so by default most server
所以在默认情况下
infrastructures do not support
大部分的服务器设施是
Multipath TCP.
不支持 Multipath TCP 的
This means that you will need to
也就是说  你需要
update or change your server
更新或修改你的
infrastructure to start
服务器设施  让它开始
supporting Multipath TCP.
支持 Multipath TCP
However, there is good news.
然而  我们带来了好消息
If you are using one of the many
如果你在某些知名的
load balances from one of the
供应商那里购买了负载均衡器
famous venders, there's a very
很可能
high chance that this vender
这个供应商已经
already supports Multipath TCP.
支持了Multipath TCP
So ask your server team, ask
所以请询问你的服务器团队
them to check the manual of the
请他们查看他们使用的
load balancer that they are
负载均衡器手册
Maybe ask the vender if they
你也可以询问你的供应商
support Multipath TCP, and if
他们是否支持 Multipath TCP
they do all you have to do is
如果他们支持的话
you enable it in the
你所要做的就只是
configuration of your servers,
在你的服务器配置中启用它
and from that moment on you're
从那一刻起
good to go to start using
你就可以开始使用
Multipath TCP.
Multipath TCP 了
If, however, you are using Linux
然而  如果你的服务器
on your server infrastructure,
使用的是 Linux
the mainstream Linux kernel
主流的 Linux 内核
doesn't yet support Multipath
目前尚未支持 Multipath
TCP, however there's the new
TCP 但是在这个网站上
Linux kernel which is available
有一种新的 Linux 内核
at this website that you can
你可以下载安装
install and that will be able to
它可以
provide Multipath TCP to your
为你的服务器提供 Multipath TCP
On this website, you will find
在这个网站上
AWS and instructions for Google
你可以找到 AWS 和 Google
Compute Engine to install
Compute Engine 安装
Multipath TCP.
Multipath TCP 的说明
And we are also working together
我们也跟
with the open source community
这个新的 Linux 内核的开源社区
of this new Linux kernel to
一起合作来进行维护
And also we are working with the
另外  我们跟开源社区一起
open source community to make
合作  使这个
this Multipath TCP code
Multipath TCP 的代码
available in the mainstream
可以用于主流内核
kernel, so that all the
使所有
distributions, all the Linux
版本  所有的 Linux
distributions are getting it by
版本都可以默认获取
Now if you have your server
现在如果你有你的
infrastructure and you have a
服务器设施  并且有一些
bunch of backend servers that
在负载均衡器背后的
are sitting behind the load
后端服务器
balancer, a Linux load balancer,
我是说 Linux 的负载均衡器
all what you'll need to do in
要想在你的服务器环境中
your server infrastructure to
获取 Multipath TCP
get Multipath TCP in this
你所要做的
environment, is that you update
就只是在这个负载均衡器上
the Linux kernel on this load
更新你的 Linux 内核
balancer, you put an HTTP proxy
你可以在上面放一个 HTTP 代理服务器
on top of it like HAProxy or
比如 HAProxy 或者
nginx, and from that moment on
nginx  然后从那一刻起
you're good to go and you can
一切就绪
start using Multipath TCP.
你就可以开始使用 Multipath TCP了
So at the end of this week when
所以  在这周结束后
you go back to your companies,
当你们回到公司
go and talk to your server team
去跟你们的服务器团队聊聊
and tell them to get the
告诉他们把
infrastructure ready for
服务器为
Multipath TCP.
Multipath TCP 做好准备
So, once you have your server
当你的服务器
infrastructure ready to go, then
准备好以后
you can start looking at the
然后你就可以开始
connections that you have inside
查看你的 app 中的
your applications and which one
连接  以及它们中的哪些
would benefit the most from
可以从 Multipath TCP 受益最多
We are exposing the Multipath
我们公开的 Multipath
TCP service type which is
TCP 服务
providing two types of different
使用 MPTCP
services using MPTCP.
提供两种不同模式的服务
The first one is the handover
第一个是一个交接模式
mode which provides a high
为你的长时间连接
reliability for your long length
提供高度的可靠性
The second is the interactive
第二个是一个交互模式
mode, the mode that we are using
就是我们在 Siri 上使用的那个模式
And this one provides a low
这个模式为你的
latency response for your
交互性的和对延迟敏感的连接
interactive and latency
保证了较低的响应延迟
So let's start with the handover
我们从交接模式开始
The handover mode is able to
交接模式可以
move traffic from Wi-Fi to cell
把数据流从 Wi-Fi 移动到数据网络
and from cell back to Wi-Fi.
以及从数据网络移回 Wi-Fi
Whenever you are in a network
当你处于一个
that has good Wi-Fi coverage and
Wi-Fi 覆盖很好的网络环境中时
to choose to opt into the
你可以选择进入
handover mode, what will happen
交接模式
is you will create a connection
然后你会仅在 Wi-Fi 网络中
only on the Wi-Fi link and we
创建一个连接
will only be using the Wi-Fi
我们将只使用 Wi-Fi 网络
link, no cellular data usage at
不用使用任何蜂窝数据
If however now the user is
不过  如果用户正在
walking out of the Wi-Fi zone
走出 Wi-Fi 区域
and the Wi-Fi signal is getting
并且 Wi-Fi 信号正在变弱
worse, when we realize that this
当我们发现这个情况时
is happening, we will bring up
我们就会打开
the cellular link and we will
蜂窝数据网络
create a TCP subflow on the
在蜂窝数据接口
cellular interface, so from that
创建一个 TCP 子流
moment on your application will
从那时起你的 app
be using the cellular data.
将开始使用蜂窝数据
If now the user is walking back
如果现在用户正在
into good Wi-Fi, what happens is
回到 Wi-Fi 信号好的区域
we will tear down the cellular
我们会再次关掉数据网络
link again and move all traffic
将所有的数据流
back onto the Wi-Fi link.
都移回到 Wi-Fi 网络
This allows us to basically
这允许我们
minimize the cellular data usage
不惜一切代价的最小化蜂窝数据用量
We encourage you to use it for
我们鼓励你把它用在
your persistent and long length
你的常用的长时间的连接上
Those kind of connections which
这些连接是你无法
you cannot easily restart or
轻易重启的  或者无法从最开始
restart from the beginning,
重启的
those connections would benefit
这种连接会从
the most from the handover mode.
交接模式中获益最多
Now, as I mentioned, Multipath
正如我所提到的  Multipath
TCP is being part of Wi-Fi
TCP 现在是 Wi-Fi
Assist, and in Wi-Fi Assist we
Assist 的一部分，而在 Wi-Fi Assist 中
have limits that try to limit
我们设置了一些限制条件来
the amount of data that we are
限制我们用数据网络发送的
sending on the cellular link.
数据量
So we encourage you to use the
所以我们鼓励你们
handover mode only for low
只在低容量的连接中
volume connections,
使用交接模式
because if you hit the Wi-Fi
因为如果你达到了 Wi-Fi
Assist limit we will stop using
Assist 的上限  我们会停止使用
the cellular link because we
数据网络连接  因为我们
don't want your application to
不希望你的 app
show up as the one that is
看起来是
consuming the most cellular
消耗过多数据网络的那种
data, so be mindful when you are
所以请记住当你
choosing the handover mode for
在为你的连接选择
your connections.
交接模式时
Don't use it for your bulk data
不要用于大型的数据传输
transfer where you are
不要几 GB 几 GB 的
downloading gigabytes and
下载数据
And the handover mode is
从周一开始
available right away in the
你在拿到的第一个测试版中
first beta that you are getting
就可以使用交接模式服务
Now, let's get on to the
那么让我们继续
interactive mode, the mode that
谈谈交互模式
is trying to reduce the latency
这个模式可以为你的
for your latency sensitive and
对延迟敏感的和抗活跃的连接
anti-active connections.
减少数据延迟
Whenever you're using the
当你开始使用
interactive mode, we will bring
交互模式时
up both Wi-Fi and cell right
我们马上会同时使用 Wi-Fi 网络和数据网络
away, even if Wi-Fi is in a good
即使 Wi-Fi 的信号很好
state, because we want to
因为我们希望
schedule the traffic in such a
可以立刻安排好数据流
way so that we are reducing the
以减少数据的延迟
We will still prefer the Wi-Fi
我们会首选 Wi-Fi 接口
interface, but as soon as we
但是一旦我们发现
realize Wi-Fi is not good
Wi-Fi 信号不够好
enough, we will not hesitate to
我们会毫不犹豫地
start sending data on the
使用数据网络来发送数据
So use it for your very
所以，在你的
interactive latency sensitive
交互性极强和对延迟非常敏感的
flows, the kinds of flows that
数据流上使用它  这种数据流
are not transmitting a lot of
并不会传输大量的数据
data, again, because we have the
因为我们设置了
Wi-Fi Assist limit that we are
Wi-Fi Assist 上限
applying and so if your flows
所以如果你的数据流
are hitting this limit we will
达到了这个上限
stop using the cellular link.
我们会停止使用数据网络
Multipath TCP will try to reduce
Multipath TCP 会尽最大努力
latency as much as it can for
来减少这些
those kind of connections.
连接的数据延迟
It will incur some cellular data
它会消耗一定的蜂窝数据
costs, and we will be giving
你们会在接下来的一个
this to you in an upcoming Beta
测试版中看到
release for you to start using
并可以开始使用
So now we have the server
现在我们有了服务器
infrastructure, we have chosen
也选好了
which connections would benefit
哪些连接可以从
from the handover mode, which
交接模式获益  哪些
connections would benefit from
连接可以从
the interactive mode.
交互模式获益
Now you can start using the
你现在可以开始使用
URLSession configuration
URLSession 配置属性
property to opt in your
来把 API 用到你的
connections to this API.
连接上
And we are exposing it in a very
我们用一个很简单的方法展示它
All what you need to do is you
你要做的就是
need to set the Multipath
在你的 URLSession 的配置属性中
service type in your URLSession
设置你想要的 Multipath 服务种类
You can choose between the
你可以在
handover mode or the interactive
交接模式和交互模式
mode, and from that point on
之间选择  然后你就可以
you're good to go.
开始使用了
Your connections will try to use
你的连接会尝试使用
Multipath TCP and they will
Multipath TCP 并且
benefit from it.
从中获益
Now in order to use it, you will
为了使用它
need to add the capability
你需要在
Multipath in X-code so that you
Xcode 中添加 Multipath
can start using it.
然后才能开始使用
Now, this brings me to one last
这就是
thing that I need to talk about
我今天需要讲的最后一件事
and this is the Aggregation
即聚合模式
Now, imagine you're connected to
现在  想像一下  你已经联入
Wi-Fi and it's providing you one
Wi-Fi  并且它每秒钟
megabyte per second in terms of
向你提供 1MB 的通过量
On the other side you have
另一方面
cellular and it is also giving
你还有蜂窝数据
you one megabyte per second of
它也每秒钟提供 1MB 的通过量
Wouldn't it be good if you can
如果你可以把
combine both together into one
它们结合到一起
big link that gives you two
变成一个更大的网络  每秒提供
megabytes per seconds?
2MB 的通过量  不是很好吗
Multipath TCP is providing
Multipath TCP 正是为你
exactly this.
提供了这个服务
It allows for aggregate the
它允许将
capacities of multiple links
多个网络的不同容量
into one byte connection.
结合成一个更大的连接
So this Aggregation Mode is
我们把这个聚合模式
available to you for
提供给你们用于实验
experimentation.
.
And why is it experimentation?
为什么说是实验呢
Well, if we are aggregating the
如果我们把
capacities of both links
两种网络的容量结合起来
together, we are consuming quite
我们会消耗一些
a little bit of cellular data.
蜂窝数据
So we want you to think about
我们希望你们能够想一想
what kind of connections do you
在你的 app 中
have in your application that
有哪些连接是可以
would benefit from a little bit
通过一个稍高的
higher throughput, at the cost
但是以蜂窝数据用量为代价的通过量
of cellular data usage?
而受益呢
If you want to use the
如果你想要使用
Aggregation Mode, what you need
聚合模式  你只需要
to do is you go into developer
进入你手机上的
settings on your phones, you
开发者设置
flip the switch to enable the
滑动滑块来启用
aggregation mode, and from that
聚合模式  然后
moment on you can start
从那时起
experimenting with the
你就可以开始实验
aggregation URLSession
aggregation URLSession
configuration property.
配置属性了
This mode on customer devices,
这个模式在
it will not be available.
用户的设备上是不可用的
So you can start experimenting
所以你可以
with the Aggregation Mode in an
在接下来的一个测试版中
upcoming Beta release.
开始测试聚合模式
So, let's recap.
那么  让我们来总结一下
In iOS we are very well aware of
在 iOS 中  我们非常清楚
this problem of using multiple
在移动设备上
interfaces on mobile devices.
使用不同接口的问题
We have Wi-Fi Assist since iOS
我们从 iOS 9 开始开发了 Wi-Fi Assist
9, and we see a great benefit in
我们看到使用 Wi-Fi Assist 有很多好处
Now in iOS 11, we are pushing
在 iOS 11 中  我们进一步对它进行了升级
We are adding Multipath
我们在 Wi-Fi Assist 中添加了 Multipath
protocols into Wi-Fi Assist.
协议
And this protocol Multipath TCP
而在 iOS 11 中  这个协议  即 Multipath TCP
is open as a public API in iOS
是作为一个公开 API 开源
You can use it for the handover
你可以在你的 app 中使用它的交接模式
mode or for the Interactive Mode
或者是交互模式
to improve your user experience
来进一步提高你的
inside your applications.
用户体验
So with this, you will now have
说了这么多  你们接下来有一段
a little break.
休息时间
This was the first part of the
这是网络架构部分的
networking session.
上半场
After the break, you will get
休息结束后，会继续
the second part.
下半场
In this second part we will
在下半场会议中
talking about new exciting APIs
将会谈到在 URLSession 层面的一些
at URLSession layer that will
好用的 API
improve the networking for your
以优化你的 app 的
applications.
网络结构
Thank you.
谢谢